这真是世上最美的订婚戒指
That is the most beautiful engagement ring ever!
你一定很了解 你买过一大堆
You should know, you bought like a billion of them.
你就没拿到
You didn't get one.
- 好 就是今晚了   - 你要怎么进行？
- Tonight's the big night.     - How will you ask her?
保证完美 我会带她上她最爱的餐厅
It'll be perfect. We'll go to her favorite restaurant.
我要送她一瓶她很喜欢的香槟
I'll get her a bottle of the champagne she really loves,
那她就知道有多贵了
therefore knows how expensive it is.
然后等酒斟好了 我不会敬酒 我会向她求婚
Then, when the glasses are full, instead of proposing a toast, I'll propose.
- 啊哦   - 好棒喔
- Aw.     - Sounds perfect!
你会搞砸 让我来吧
You'll mess up. Let me do it.
我才不会搞砸
I won't mess up.
要是她说不 戒指可以给我吗？
If she says no, can I have the ring?
- 她不会说不的   - 要是呢？
- She won't say no.     - If?
- 嘿   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
嘿 摩妮卡
Hey, Monica.
- 还给我   - 吞下去了
- Give it.     - It's gone.
菲比
Phoebe.
- 嘿   - 嘿 摩妮卡
- Hey.     - Hey, Monica!
我们在接吻喔
We're practically kissing.
老友记 第六季 第二十四集
- 大家好   - 嘿
- Hey.     - Hey.
晚上有人有空吗？我主管要主持救助贫童慈善会
Anyone free tonight? My boss is hosting a charity event for kids.
我带越多人去越有面子
And the more people I bring, the better I look.
摩妮卡？钱德？
So Monica, Chandler?
摩妮卡和钱德不能去 我们要去吃饭 记得吗？
We can't go. We're going to dinner. Remember?
- 天哪 真抱歉   - 干嘛这么激动？
- Oh, my God. I'm so sorry.     - What's the big deal?
我只是很气 瑞秋不记得我们要去哪里
I just get mad when Rachel doesn't remember where we're going.
你们要去哪里？
Where are you going?
- 那你们呢？ - 酒品免费？
- How about you guys?     - Open bar?
- 应该是   - 我可以为孩子们喝酒
- I think so.     - I can do that for the kids.
那我也要去 我现在有收入 也该回报社会了
I'll come. I'm making money now. It's time I give some back.
你也可以把欠我的钱还给我
You could give back the money you owe me.
好啊 那你办慈善晚会啊
Okay. Have a benefit.
罗斯 你晚上可以 来参加慈善晚会吗？
Ross, can you come to a charity event tonight?
不行 我跟伊丽莎白有约
Oh. No, I have plans with Elizabeth.
你已经在为孩童贡献心力了
Oh. You're already doing your part for the kids.
抱歉 再过几天 她要去夏令营去当辅导员
It's our last night together before she leaves for camp. To be a counselor.
罗斯 我问你 撇开笑话不提 这段感情要往哪里走？
I have a question. All jokes aside. Where is this relationship going?
等等 撇开笑话不提？我可不同意
Wait a minute. All jokes aside? I didn't agree to that.
- 你认为你们可以长久吗？ - 不知道
- Do you see this as long-term thing?     - I don't know.
你比她大12岁喔
You are 12 years older than her.
等等 你们都这么认为吗？
Wait a minute. Does everyone feel this way?
- 有点   - 抱歉 有点
- Yeah.     - Yeah, sort of.
我以为你们只是开玩笑 我都不知道
Uh, wow. Uh, I thought you were making jokes. I had no idea.
不过你们都错了 没错 我们是有年龄上的差异
You guys are wrong. Yes, there is a chronological age difference.
但是我都感觉不到 为什么？因为她很成熟
But I never notice it, because she is very mature.
况且我根本不在意你们的看法 跟她交往的是我 不是你们
It doesn't matter what you guys think. I'm dating Elizabeth, not you.
她昨晚可不是这么说的
Not what she said last night.
他配她就够幼雅
See, now he could date her.
你愿意嫁给我吗？
Will you marry me?
喂 嫁给我
Hey, you marry me.
怎么了 小精灵们？
What's going on, little elves?
今晚很重要 我们想祝你好运
It's the big night. We wanted to wish you luck.
- 戒指带了吗？ - 在口袋里
- Yeah. Have the ring?     - In my pocket.
噢
Oh.
- 菲比   - 哦 哈哈
- Pheebs.     - Oh. Ha, ha.
麻烦你们出去 我想给她惊喜 她会看出来
Will you guys get out of here? I want this to be a surprise, and she's gonna know.
没错 你们快出去
Yeah, guys. Get out of here.
大家好
Hey. Hi, guys.
- 你好漂亮   - 谢谢
- You look beautiful.     - Aww. Thank you.
怎么了？
What's going on?
我们只是...
We're just really...
要参加慈善晚会觉得很兴奋
excited about this charity event that we have to go to.
- 给你   - 谢谢
- Here.     - Thank you.
现在是怎样？
So what's going on here?
这是一场不喊价拍卖会
Well, uh, this is a silent auction.
要卖的东西都在这里 你写下竞标价
They lay the stuff here. You write down your offer.
出价最高的就是得主
The highest bid gets it.
我知道什么叫不喊价拍卖会 我是说你的头发怎么了？
No. I know what a silent auction is. What's going on with your hair?
- 怎么说？ - 没什么 真的很好看
- Uh, why?     - No, it's nice.
瑞秋 欢迎 你带了一位朋友来
Nice to see you. So glad you brought someone.
一位？我带了两位
Someone? I brought people.
汤普森先生 这位是菲比 菲比 这位是汤普森先生
This is Phoebe. Phoebe, this is Mr. Thompson.
- 他是我的部门主管   - 哦 嗨
- He's the head of my department.     - Oh, hi.
- 我还带了我的朋友乔伊...   - 虾子吐司
- And I also brought my friend Joey.     - Ohh! Shrimp toast!
我不知道他在哪里
You know, I don't know where he is.
希望你会参加竞标 瑞秋
I hope you're gonna bid.
我正打算投标这趟巴黎之旅
Actually, I was about to bid on this lovely trip to Paris.
- 有眼光   - 是吗
- Nice choice.     - Yeah.
- 祝你好运   - 谢谢
- Good luck.     - Thank you.
好
Ha.
20元
Okay, $20.00.
把门关上 把门关上
Shut the door! Shut the door!
怎么了？
What's going on?
对面的男生在朝我们丢水球
Guys across the hall are throwing water balloons.
你们得报警 我都这样对付我家那栋的小孩
Call the police. That's what I did to kids in my building.
这是水球仗 是我们挑起的
No, it's a water balloon fight. We started it.
哦
Oh. Hmm.
听我说 我来问你晚上要不要去看戏
Um, I just stopped by to see if you wanted to see this play tonight.
这出戏应该很棒 导演...
Um, it's excellent. The director is...
- 谁把神风特攻队都喝了？ - 没有 都在水球里
- Who drank all the kamikazes?     - Nobody. We put them in here!
- 你要吗？ - 不要
- You want some?     - No, I... Okay, okay.
- 好 我可以跟你讲下话吗？ - 当然可以
- Could I talk to you for a second?     - Yeah, sure.
所以你要去看戏吗？
Um, so this play, um, what do you think?
- 它的剧评很好...   - 攻击
- It's gotten great reviews.     - Attack!
- 放下水球   - 你们才放下
- Put your balloons down!     - You put your balloons down!
统统都把水球放下
Everybody put their balloons down!
这可是高级西装
Now, this is a nice suit!
下项拍卖品 是巴黎浪漫之旅
Our next item is the romantic trip to Paris.
由艾弥尔亚历山大 以2千3百元的高价得标
It goes to Emil Alexander with a high bid of $2300.
只差一点
Oh! So close!
你们看 我拿了几杯酒
Hey, you guys, look. Got me some drinks.
- 你在干什么？ - 不用钱嘛
- What are you doing?     - Open bar.
最后是今晚的最大项目
Finally, our biggest item of the night.
22呎豪华帆船
The 22-foot Gentleman's Daysailer sailboat.
得标金额高达两万元
The winning bid was a whopping $20,000.
我赢了
I won!
那是我猜的
That was my guess!
什么？什么？
What? What? What?
我猜两万
I guessed $20,000.
乔伊 这是拍卖会 你不是猜 是买
Joey, it is an auction. You don't guess. You buy!
什么？
What?
我没有两万
I don't have $20,000.
恭喜你购得新船 乔伊崔比亚尼
Congratulations on your new boat, Joey Tribbiani.
坐下啦
Joey, sit down.
别理她 开心就好
Forget her. You enjoy this. Whoo!
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
"一个国家...
"One nation...
在神之下 不可分割 全民拥有自由公正"
under God, indivisible, with liberty and justice for all."
我记得是这样背 香槟来了
Ha, ha. I remembered it. The champagne is here.
- 你没事吧？ - 我很好
- Are you okay?     - Yes. Yes.
你好吗？
I'm good. Are you good?
一切都好吗？
Are you perfect?
还好
Yeah. I'm okay.
其实我有点冷 外套可以借我吗？
I'm a little cold. Can I have your jacket?
可以
Oh. Yeah.
不行 我的外套不能借你
Uh, no, you can't have my jacket.
因为那样我就会冷
Because then I would be cold.
你要是觉得会冷 应该自己带外套
If you thought you'd be cold, you should have brought a jacket.
除此之外 你好吗？
Uh, other than that, are you okay?
你真的没事吗？
Are you sure you're okay?
我真的很好
Yes. I'm fine.
我这段日子一直都很好 我觉得...
In fact, I've been fine for a long time now and I think...
都是托你的福
the reason is you.
好甜蜜喔
That's sweet.
好...
Okay. Um.
认识你之前 我的人生微不足道
Before I met you, I had really little life.
我无法想像一个人...
And I couldn't imagine growing old...
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
- 我知道 不过让我说完   - 我的天哪 理查
- I know. But let me say it.     - Oh, my God. Richard.
什么？我是钱德
What? I'm Chandler.
噢 是理查
Oh, that's Richard.
天哪 也许他看不见我们 理查
Maybe he won't see us. Richard!
- 摩妮卡 钱德   - 嘿
- Monica. Chandler.     - Hey.
我不知道我为什么要抱你
I don't know why I did that.
- 见到你真好   - 彼此彼此 你把头发留长了
- It's good to see you.     - You too. You let your hair grow.
啊对 你一直希望我留长
Yeah. Oh, that's right, you always wanted me to.
你又开始留胡子了
I see your mustache is back.
我的鼻子感到寂寞
Well, my nose got lonely.
你没留胡子 很好
And you don't have a mustache, which is good. Ha, ha.
我是钱德 我一不舒服就开玩笑
I'm Chandler. I make jokes when I'm uncomfortable.
抱歉 丽莎 摩妮卡 钱德 我们交往过
I'm sorry. Lisa, Monica, Chandler. We used to date.
理查 我们的事应该保密
Richard! No one's supposed to know about us!
我又来了
See, I did it again.
- 钱德 我们坐下吧   - 好 我坐
- Chandler, sit down.     - I'll sit down.
很高兴见到你们
Good to see you.
您的桌子准备好了
Your table is ready, sir.
- 很高兴遇见你们   - 好
- Oh. Good to see you guys.     - Yes.
这一桌也是空的
If you prefer, this table's available.
一起坐应该不错
That might be fun.
你在想什么？
What were you thinking?
我不知道这是拍卖会
I didn't know it was an auction.
我以为是猜一猜
I figured I'd take a guess.
帮助慈善团体 免费得帆船
Help a charity. Free boat!
慈善团体为什么要送帆船？
Why would a charity give away a free boat?
- 我哪知道 做慈善吗？ - 噢
- I don't know. Charity?     - Oh!
你就买吧
Well, just buy the damn boat.
菲比 你喝够了吧？
Phoebe, don't you think you've had enough to drink?
我只是在帮助儿童
I'm just helping the kids.
你喝酒怎么能帮助儿童？
How is you drinking helping the kids?
我喝得越多 孩子们能喝的就越少
Because the more I drink, the less there is for the kids to drink.
崔比亚尼先生 你慷慨解囊
Mr. Tribbiani. Your contribution brings us...
让兴建活动中心的事大有进展
a big step closer to building the youth center.
我很好奇 那艘船值多少？
Just out of curiosity, how much is that boat worth?
差不多是1万9
I think it was valued at 19,000.
我猜得蛮准的
Hey, I was pretty close.
坏消急
Uh, so, bad news.
我不能买那艘船 我没有钱
Um, I can't buy the boat. I don't have any money.
乔伊 你真幽默
Joey! Joey, good one!
你真会演
Good! Very good!
- 好吧 我要问人了   - 你不能走 乔伊
- So, uh, I think I'm gonna take off now.     - You can't leave, Joey!
你答应要买船 那具有约束力
You agreed to buy that boat. It is a contract.
而且你走了 我的主管会宰了我
Plus, if you leave, my boss is gonna kill me.
那怎么办？我没有那么多钱
Well, what am I gonna do, Rach? I don't have that kind of money.
我知道 好...
I know. Okay, okay, okay, okay.
好 这样吧
This is what we'll do.
我们去找出价第二高的人 然后让他们去买
We'll go to the next highest bidder, and we'll let them buy it.
你只要付差价
Then you're just gonna pay the difference.
好
Okay.
这些小孩要活动中心干嘛
I don't know why the kids need a youth center anyway.
放了学跟我一样看电视就好了 我现在也蛮好的
They should just watch TV after school like I did. And I turned out fine.
但是不优秀
Not great.
我们躲在洗手间里...
So we're hiding in the bathroom...
然后我溜出来 但摩妮卡还没出来 她父母就进去了
Then I sneak out. But before Monica can, her parents come in.
于是我躲到浴帘后面
I hid in the shower, next thing you know...
接着他们就在地上做起来了
they're going at it on the floor.
我的天哪
Oh, my God!
我有一个 我有一个
I got a good one.
我有一次撞见我父母 跟同一个男人做爱
I once walked in on both my parents making love to the same guy.
遇见你们真的好开心 我想敬酒
It's so great seeing you guys again. I'd like to make a toast.
正如一位诗人所说 "在友谊的甜蜜里
Uh, as a poet once said, "In the sweetness of friendship...
尽情欢笑 分享欢乐吧
let there be laughter and sharing of pleasures...
人心正是...
for in the dew of little things...
从中获得朝气 焕然一新"
the heart finds its morning and is refreshed."
啊哦
Aw.
什么？
What?
天哪 你们两个
Oh, my God! You guys!
在你开口之前 我们有事要说 你猜我们吃饭时遇见谁？
Before you say anything, have we got a story for you. Guess who we bumped into?
- 谁？ - 理查
- Who?     - Richard!
哦 哦
Oh. Oh.
你不是要跟伊丽莎白约会？
I thought you were going out with Elizabeth.
没错 但是她忙着打水球仗
I was. Uh, she was a little busy with a water balloon fight.
有时大人就是会有事无法脱身
Sometimes grownups have commitments they can't get out of.
也许她真的太年轻了
Maybe she is too young for me.
当我看到她跟朋友横冲直撞 我觉得我好像保姆
When I was over there, I felt like I was a babysitter.
我终于开始了解你们说的话 我不知道该怎么办
I finally see what you were talking about. I don't know what to do.
你可以比较这段感情的利弊
Just weigh the good stuff about the relationship against the bad.
我当初就是这样... 比较东西的
That's what I did when I first started weighing stuff.
好 嗯 我比她大12岁
Okay, um, bad stuff. I'm 12 years older than she is.
学校发现会开除你
If school finds out, you're fired.
- 她要离开3个月   - 去参加夏令营
- She's leaving for three months.     - For camp.
好 呃...
Okay, good stuff. Um...
她很甜很漂亮...
Well, she's sweet and pretty and...
罗斯 你只需要问你自己 你看得见未来吗？
The only question you need to ask is, do you see a future?
你能想像跟她结婚吗？
Do you see yourself marrying her?
天哪 你已经娶她了对不对？
My God. You did it already. You married her, didn't you?
没有啦 我只是...
No, I didn't do that. It's just...
好吧 老实说 我觉得我们没什么未来
Honestly, no, I don't see a big future with her.
那这就是你的答案了
Okay, I think that's your answer.
我得告诉她 我最恨这个步骤了
I gotta talk to her. I hate this part.
你必须忘了伊丽莎白 你要是不小心...
Forget Elizabeth. If you're not careful...
今年可能会结不到婚
you may not get married at all this year.
瑞秋 瑞秋
Rach, Rach.
- 出第2高价的人在1号桌   - 太好了
- Next highest bidder is at table one.     - Great.
标到巴黎之旅的人坐4号桌 噢 好
The guy who got the Paris trip is at table four.
你干嘛管谁赢得巴黎之旅？
You care about the guy who won the Paris trip?
那是双人之旅
It's a trip for two.
失陪了
Excuse me.
抱歉 标到巴黎之旅的人 在这一桌吗？
Excuse me. Is the person who won the Paris trip at this table?
- 我就是   - 抱歉
- That was me.     - Oh. Enchante.
有没有一位波芒先生？
Uh, is there a Mr. Bowmont at this table?
- 我就是   - 啊
- That's me.     - Ah.
你好 你今天走运了 波芒先生
Hello. This is your lucky day, Mr. Bowmont.
那艘帆船又要卖了
The, uh, Gentleman Daysailer has become available again.
你开了1万8的价格 不是吗？
I believe you made a bid of $18,000?
你得付钱 那不是猜好玩的
You have to pay that. It's not just a guess.
没标到船 我还松了一口气
I was actually relieved, uh, I didn't win the boat.
我老婆会宰了我
My wife would've killed me.
不会吧？她会爱死这艘船
Are you kidding? She'll love this boat!
- 是啊 尊夫人芳名？ - 她叫潘
- What is your wife's name?     - It's Pam.
潘 天哪 想像一下 "潘号"
It's Pam. Just imagine this. The Pam.
啊哦
Aw.
我想她不会喜欢
I don't think she'd like that.
那想像..."波芒先生号"
Okay. Uh, imagine this: The Mr. Bowmont.
噢
Ooh.
还是不要了
I don't think so.
让我为你描绘一下
Okay, look. Let me paint you a little picture. All right.
你在哈德逊河上航行 风吹过你的头...左手
You are setting sail up the Hudson. You've got the wind in your ha... Arms.
你得到你企盼已久的安宁
You get all that peace and quiet you've always wanted.
你回到大自然怀抱 你可以钓鱼
You get back to nature. You can go fishing.
你可以买一顶帽子 让大家叫你船长
You get one of those hats, people call you captain.
等你老了就是老船长
And then when you're old, Cappy.
管他的 不买说不过去 我买了
What the hell. It's for a good cause. All right!
- 别想 船是我的   - 什么？
- No way! It's mine!     - What?
你刚才说的那些事我也要
The stuff you said, I want that!
但是乔伊 你没有两万元
But, Joey, you don't have $20,000!
管他的我分期 怎样都好 我要"波芒先生号"
Who cares? I'll make payments! I want the Mr. Bowmont!
天哪 你们回来了
Oh, my God! You're back!
让我看 让我看你的手
Let me see your hand!
你为什么要看我的手？
Why do you want to see my hand?
我想看你手上拿的垃圾
I want to see what's in your hand, the trash.
好脏 你最好拿去扔
Ew, it's all dirty. You should throw this out.
好
Okay.
- 你们搞什么？ - 怎么回事？
- What did you just do?     - What happened?
- 理查也在 我无法开口   - 不会吧
- Richard was there. I couldn't do it.     - Oh, no.
我要延到明天 给她惊喜 却被你们破坏了
I was gonna do it tomorrow and surprise her. Now you've ruined it.
我们没有破坏
We didn't.
谁会一进门就要看别人的手？
Who walks into a room and asks to see a person's hands?
算命师 修指甲的小姐 手部医生...
A palm reader, a manicurist, a hand doctor.
- 手套推销员   - 漂亮
- Glove salesman.     - Good one!
真惨 我该怎么办？
This is terrible. What am I gonna do?
她只是在怀疑 又不确定 你可以唬她
She only suspects something. So just throw her off the track.
也对 我可以让她觉得 我完全不考虑结婚
I'll make her think, uh, marriage is the last thing on my mind.
没错 让她相信你很害怕承诺
Yeah. Convince her you're scared of commitment.
我做得到 我练了30年
I can do that. I've had 30 years of practice.
你这个人总算有点价值了
Being you is finally gonna pay off!
我还得跑去地下室扔...
Had to go to the basement...
某个白痴小孩老是用披萨盒 把垃圾槽堵住
some idiot keeps stuffing the chute with pizza boxes.
那个家伙还是没改？
That guy's still doing that?
天哪 你们回来了 我看看你的手
Hey. My God, let me see your hand!
来不及了 她已经把垃圾拿去扔了
No, you're too late! She already took out the trash!
我跟别人分手没这么平和过
Wow. I have never had such a healthy breakup.
她表现得好成熟
She was such a grownup about it.
我觉得她一点也不幼雅
She didn't seem too immature for me.
我是不是犯了个大错？
Did I just make a huge mistake?
罗斯 等等
Ross? Wait!
伊丽莎白 太好了 我正在想说...
Elizabeth, thank God. I was just thinking about...
你最烂了
You suck!
什么？
What?
好
Okay.
分手还是有效
Breakup's still on.
她来了
Here she comes.
怎么样？我像不像不想结婚的人？
Do I look like a guy who doesn't want to get married?
像
Yeah.
还有点像法国人
And, also, a little like a French guy.
我第一次发现
I never noticed that before.
- 大家好   - 嘿
- Hey, guys.     - Hey.
你们在干什么？
What are you up to?
只是在杀时间 聊网站
Just hanging out. Talking about, uh, web sites.
哈
Ha.
有一个有趣的网站在讨论婚姻
Ahem. We saw this interesting website about marriage.
及婚姻的一无是处
How unnecessary it is.
说那只是政府监视你的方式
How it's a way for governments to keep tabs on you.
是啊 老大哥
Yeah, Big Brother. Ha, ha.
有点夸张
That's a little crazy.
不过很高兴你们总算上了 其他类别的网站
Although I am glad you're looking at other things on the Internet.
不过我就想 为什么会有人想要结婚？
Got me thinking, why would anybody want to get married?
为什么？因为要赞颂这段感情 要巩固你们的承诺
Why? To celebrate the relationship. To solidify the commitment.
要向全世界宣布你们的爱
To declare your love for one another to the world.
呃
Eh.
能知道你的反应真好
Okay. Well, that's good to know.
"波芒先生号"来了
The Mr. Bowmont's here!
摩妮卡 有一位客人 想向主厨致意 要让他进来吗？
A customer wants to compliment you. Shall I let him in?
当然 我最爱这种事了
Sure! I love this part!
- 进来吧   - 嘿
- Come on in.     - Hi.
理查
Richard.
其实我不是来向主厨致意的
I'm not here to compliment the chef.
没关系 我最讨厌客人跑来致意
Oh. I hate when people come back to compliment the chef.
好像我很闲似的
Like I've nothing better to do.
你有什么事？
What's up?
那天晚上遇见你很开心
It was great seeing you the other night.
我也很开心
Good to see you too.
你就是来说这个的？
Come down here to tell me that?
不是 我是来说别的
No. Came here to tell you something else.
我是来说我仍然爱你
Came here to tell you I still love you.